<xml>
	<name>ENGAGE</name>
	<sort_id>2</sort_id>
	<tagline>Immersive game-based learning curricular strategy for infusing computational thinking and computational fluency into middle school science. (Funding: CNS-1138497, DRL-1640141)</tagline>
	<description>
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Despite the growing demand for computer scientists, there is still only a small fraction of students enrolling in computer science courses in high schools and universities. The need for computer scientists is not limited to the computing field. Having computer science knowledge and skills will benefit students and graduates in many fields including biology, physics, chemistry, oceanography, and mathematics. Unfortunately, by the time students reach high school and university, they can have misconceptions about computer science, causing the courses to become undesirable to them. Therefore, it is important to demonstrate the relevance of computer science to students earlier in their education to encourage them to take computer science courses in the future. This project is led by PI James Lester, co-PI Bradford Mott, and co-PI Eric Wiebe at North Carolina State University, and by co-PI Kristy Boyer and co-PI David Blackburn at the University of Florida.&lt;p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Project Description&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The ENGAGE Project develops middle grade computational fluency within an immersive game-based learning environment. The project includes adapting the CS Principles high school Big Data for middle school and contextualizing it within a narrative-based learning environment. The setting of the game is an underwater research station where the main character, uses computer science and oceanography knowledge and skills to solve a mystery about problems with the fish population. ENGAGE also emphasizes teacher professional development. The setting of the game allows it to be integrated with middle school oceanography curricula and the project involves holding professional development programs to develop curricula with oceanography teachers. The curricula focuses on computational thinking in oceanography and consists of gameplay and supplementary lessons and activities to support the concepts learned in the game.	&lt;p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;For more details, go to &lt;a href="https://projects.intellimedia.ncsu.edu/engage/"&gt;https://projects.intellimedia.ncsu.edu/engage/&lt;/a &gt; &lt;/p&gt;	
		
	</description>
</xml>
